DIMITAR CHOLAKOV

Software Developer



ABOUT

Junior developer with experience in frontend, PEGA platform & full-stack development. Well-versed in different programming languages, frameworks & libraries. Knowing all stages of development for dynamic web projects. Certified in SAFe for teams agile work methodology. Code Institute Alum (graduate). Interested in UX/UI design. Likes to learn & embrace new challenges. Responsible & neat. Friendly & good team-player. Strong background in industry, logistics & sales.

+46(0) 704 06 65 46

dimitar-cholakov-website

LinkedIn in GitHub

LANGUAGES

EXPERIENCE

09.2022 - to date: UNIQA Software Service (PEGA Developer)

Part of U.CRM Team working with PEGA platform on developing apps & features for UNIQA's insurance services.

05.2022 - 07.2022: GRÖNT.org - Frontend Web Developer Intern (Internship via Lexicon education course).

07.2020 - 06.2022: Freelance work & experience gained by "Learn by doing" study principles. Build study & personal projects using various tech-stack to expand knowledge. For portfolio & additional information click *here*.

06.2016 - 07.2020: Worked in **KL Industri AB** (Sweden) & **ManPower Group AB** (Sweden) in the industry & warehousing area.

EDUCATION

Frontend Development (10.2021 - 06.2022)

Lexicon (Linkoping, Sweden)

The program is covering frontend basics, frameworks like React & Angular, working with data: SQL & MongoDB. Included company internship/practice after theory part is done.

Diploma in Software Development (09.2020 - 05.2021)

Code Institute (Dublin, Ireland) - Remote

Full-stack course that gives hands-on experience on creating employer-ready web technologies. Learning content is industry-validated & the awarded EQF level 5 diploma is credit-rated by Edinburgh's Napier University.

Five Day Coding Challenge (07.2020)

Code Institute (Dublin, Ireland) - Remote

Course, teaching the basics of coding from both theoretical & practical point of view. It's covering the three pillars of modern frontend development - HTML, CSS & JavaScript.

Business Administration (2001 - 2006)

High School of Economy 'Karl Marks' (Smolyan, Bulgaria)

SKILLS

Bootstrap

HTML 😈

CSS 🗉

JavaScript 35



- Responsive Design
- Git(Version control)
- GitHub
- UX/UI Design
- Materialize

- PEGA Platform
- Rest APIs
- jQuery
- React
- Python
- MongoDB

HOBBIES







